// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is the capital of Maharashtra?",
    answer: "Mumbai",
    options: [
      " Nagpur",
      "Satara ",
      "Pune ",
      "Mumbai"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Who is the father of Computer?",
    answer: "Charles Babbage",
    options: [
      "James Gosling ",
      "Charles Babbage",
      "Dennis Ritchin",
      "Bjarne Stroustrup"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "What is the full form of CPU?",
    answer: "Central Processing Unit",
    options: [
      "Computer Processing unit",
      "Computer Principle unit",
      "Central Processing Unit",
      "Control Processing unit "
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following language does the computer understand?",
    answer: "Computer understands only Binary Language",
    options: [
      "Computer understands only C Language",
      "Computer understands only Assembly Language",
      "Computer understands only Binary Language",
      "Computer understands only BASIC"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following computer language is written in binary codes only?",
    answer: "machine language",
    options: [
      "JAVA",
      "machine language",
      "C",
      "C#"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following is the brain of the computer?",
    answer: "Central Processing Unit",
    options: [
      "Memory",
      "Central Processing Unit",
      "Ram",
      "ROM"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a computer? ?",
    answer: "IQ",
    options: [
      "IQ",
      "Versatility",
      "Accurecy",
      "Diligence"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following is the smallest unit of data in a computer?",
    answer: "Bit",
    options: [
      "Byte",
      "GB",
      "Bit",
      "KB"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following monitor looks like a television and are normally used with non-portable computer systems?",
    answer: "CRT",
    options: [
      "CRT",
      "LED",
      "LCD",
      "Moniter"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: " Which of the following is not a type of computer code?",
    answer: "EDIC",
    options: [
      "ASCLL",
      "BCD",
      "EBCDIC",
      "EDIC"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Which of the following can access the server?",
    answer: "Web Client",
    options: [
      "Web client",
      "User",
      "Web Browser",
      "Web Server"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Which of the following is known as the language made up of binary-coded instructions?",
    answer: "Machine",
    options: [
      "Machine",
      "C",
      "BAsic",
      "High level"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Which of the following is created when a user opens an account in the computer system?",
    answer: "Subdirectory",
    options: [
      "Subdirectory",
      "MFD",
      "RFD",
      "SFD"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which of the following service allows a user to log in to another computer somewhere on the Internet?",
    answer: " Telnet",
    options: [
      "UseNet",
      "email",
      "FTP",
      " Telnet"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Which of the following is not a type of computer on the basis of operation? ?",
    answer: "Remote",
    options: [
      "analog",
      "Remote",
      "hybrid",
      "digtal"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which of the following is the first neural network computer?",
    answer: "SNARC",
    options: [
      "AM",
      "AN",
      "SNARC",
      "RFD"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: " Which of the following is used in EBCDIC?",
    answer: "Mainfarmes",
    options: [
      "Machine Code",
      "Mainfarmes",
      "Programming",
      "Super Cumputer"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "Which of the following are physical devices of a computer?",
    answer: "Hardwere",
    options: [
      "Softwere",
      "System Softwere",
      "hardwere",
      "Package"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: " Which of the following defines the assigned ordering among the characters used by the computer?",
    answer: "Collating Sequence",
    options: [
      "Accumulation",
      "Sorting",
      "Collating Sequence",
      "Unicode"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which of the following devices provides the communication between a computer and the outer world?",
    answer: "I/O",
    options: [
      "compact",
      "Strage",
      "Drivers",
      "I/O"
    ]
  },
];